Yuanyuan (Lilian) Sun

Summary-----

Master of Computer Science with productive experience in Data Processing & Machine Learning. Award-winning backend software developer with 5+ years of professional experience. Extensive background in full software development lifecycle. Exceptional problem solver with an aptitude for troubleshooting. Proficiency in OOP, SQL. Pursuing specialization in AWS Cloud SAA. Seeking 2023 summer internship: Full-Stack Software Engineer / DA / ML.

Education------

Illinois Institute of Technology, Chicago, IL, USA Suzhou University of Science and Technology, China B.S. in Computer Science and Technology Jun. 2016

M.S. in Computer Science (GPA 3.67/4.0) Dec. 2023

Skills ------

Java, Spring Framework, Spring Boot; Python (NumPy, Pandas, matplotlib, SciKit, SciPy), Flask, R; SQL, NoSQL; JavaScript, HTML/CSS, React; Linux, Git, CI/CD, AWS Cloud Services, Jenkins, Docker;

Languages: Chinese (native), English

Work Experience-----

Senior Software Engineer (Shanghai Highly Electric Co., Ltd) Shanghai, China

- Researched & selected libraries, open-source technologies for project integration. Provided estimates for web application development & test. Designed scalable service architecture.
- Re-architected tangled applications by applying a unifying framework. Improved operational efficiency, reliability, adaptability. Decreased user complaints by 65% and reduced the cost of operation & maintenance by 15%.
- Developed reusable APIs. Supported building & deployment of new products and features & tests. Implemented and executed Stress Testing on high-concurrency interfaces.
- As a **lead** developer in a machine learning project constructed a back-end project from scratch by Python, Flask. Data Cleaning & Data Processing by Pandas, NumPy. Data Visualization & Model Training.
- Led a team of software developers and testers & Coordinated with cross-functional teams. Oversaw full lifecycle of 2 software development projects with on-time delivery while staying 5% under budget.
- Mentored junior developers & summer interns.

Junior Software Engineer (Shanghai Mathartsys Co., Ltd) Shanghai, China Mar. 2017 - Mar. 2019

- Analyzed user requirements, designed functional and flexible web services by UML, collaborated with BA, QA to create detailed design documentation, unit test plans, well-documented code.
- Created RESTful APIs that served data to the JavaScript front-end based on J2EE, Spring Framework, Spring Boot. Researched and evaluated methods & techniques to resolve problems, reduced friction in development lifecycle.
- Managed & maintained 11 enterprise web applications, patched & improved features. Embraced automation, streamlined the build and deployment process. Documented and presented reports to leadership twice a month.
- Revamped web applications on Linux, improved security applications, minimized hacker attacks from 33.3% to **3.2%**.
- Fixed bugs and streamlined documented procedures to increase DevOps efficiency by 20% from 2018 to 2019.

Android System Dev Intern (Pactera Technology International Ltd.) Feb. 2016 – Jun. 2016, Shanghai, China

- Burned the Android OS source code in devices. Developed and improved features on the native applications via SDK. Cooperated with QA team to improve user interfaces.
- In the top 10% of interns in bug fix releases in the Android Framework R&D team.







